# SEAN STICKLAND

ICT Technician Turned Full Stack Software Developer

STICKLANDSM@GMAIL.COM • 021 829 780 • NZ CITIZEN

HTTPS://WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/SEAN-STICKLAND-AA26461AB/

HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/STICKLANDSM

HTTPS://WWW.PORTFOLIO.SANDCASTLEINK.NZ/

# **ABOUT ME**

I'm an early-career software developer with 9 years of experience in ICT support. Software development has been a long-standing hobby and passion of mine, and after completing <u>Dev Academy Aotearoa</u> earlier this year, I'm excited to make it my full-time career.

A few years ago, I was diagnosed with ADHD. Receiving treatment for it has been life-changing, and the newfound clarity and focus led me to enrol at Dev Academy. The bootcamp aims to simulate a real agile development team, and I emerged as one of the top students in my class.

Due to my coding aptitude and prior experience, I frequently assumed the role of team lead. I scoped out the projects, provided guidance whenever others were blocked, and led the backend development of our Node applications.

Combining my extensive industry experience in the IT world, with my enthusiasm for software development, I am an ideal candidate for a software development team.

# **SKILLS & EXPERTISE**

- Proficient in coding with TypeScript, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, Tailwind, and more.
- Experienced in using Git and GitHub, code reviews, and RESTful API services.
- At Dev Academy, I demonstrated the ability to quickly grasp new concepts and technologies, which allowed me to excel in my coursework.
- Previous experience as an ICT Technician for various software companies provides a unique understanding of the software business.
- Developed automation scripts to streamline ICT tasks and increase efficiency.

# **EXPERIENCE**

**Dev Academy** | Jan 2023 - May 2023 | Student

- Gained experience in using modern web development tools and techniques, while also focusing on essential human skills such as providing feedback, collaboration, and working in agile teams.
- For my final project, I led a team in creating a restaurant ordering app, where I took charge of coding the back-end and helped with much of the front-end.
- I made extensive unit tests for the app to ensure that it met the highest standards of functionality and user experience. This allowed me to showcase my skills in both technical development and leadership.
- See the app here: <a href="https://waitless.sandcastleink.nz/table/1/menu">https://waitless.sandcastleink.nz/table/1/menu</a>

# **Tekne LTD** | Dec 2020 - Dec 2022 |

ICT Technician

- Developed strong organizational and communication skills needed to effectively manage the IT needs of many small and large businesses across NZ.
- Collaborated with team members and clients to solve complex IT challenges, which further developed problem-solving skills and built strong relationships.
- Demonstrated the ability to rapidly adapt to new clients, environments, and systems, expanding knowledge and skills with ease.

# Vista Entertainment | Apr 2019 - Nov 2020 |

ICT Technician

- Stayed up to date with industry trends and best practices to improve system performance and security, effectively managing risks.
- Developed initial coding skills by writing automation scripts to expedite computer setup processes, gaining experience in scripting and automation.
- Collaborated with developers to resolve routine hardware and software issues, further developing my technical and problem-solving skills.

# Sony Mobile, Oceania | Feb 2015 - Dec 2018 |

Service Warranty & Training Manager

Managed staff training, repairs, refunds, and dealt with tribunal cases against Sony.

# Sony Electronics, Oceania | Oct 2013 - May 2015 |

Customer Support Representative, IT Specialist

Customer facing consumer support for VAIO laptops.

#### **EDUCATION**

2023 - Dev Academy Aotearoa

Certificate in Applied Software Development

2010 - Auckland University of Technology

Certificate in Computer & Mathematical Sciences

This included courses on Java programming and calculus

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

During my graduation ceremony at Dev Academy, my teacher applauded my aptitude for programming and leadership.

In recognition of my exceptional work at Sony Mobile, I was sent to Sweden to talk at their annual training conference.

#### **PERSONAL**

In my spare time, apart from coding silly word games, I enjoy playing guitar badly, watching terrible action movies with my friends, and seeing indie rock bands.

#### **REFERENCES**

See below from Dev Academy.

Others available upon request.

# Level 5, 12 Morgan Street Level 2, 275 Cuba Street Auckland 1011 Wellington 6011

28 July 2023

To Sean's future employers,

Sean attended and successfully completed the Dev Academy Bootcamp at the Auckland campus in 2023.

As a Lead teacher, I taught and worked closely with Sean throughout this time and I regarded him as one of our most advanced students. He applied himself to every challenge and did so with curiosity.

He seemed to have a natural talent for programming and I was always impressed with the quality of his work. He tended to research his approach well and deliver features in a timely manner. He would also consider proper functionality as well as edge-cases. For example, he delivered server-side API code using database returning arrays to improve performance. This was something he discovered himself.

Sean was an ambitious and reliable teammate among his peers and the quality of their final project reflected his influence. This included presentations which he delivered with confidence.

I appreciated his straight-forward communication style, especially when it came to giving and receiving feedback. Lastly, I enjoyed his sometimes twisted sense of humour.

I recommend Sean as a well-rounded, talented developer and wish him success in his career and chosen craft.

Sincerely,

Alex Coaton (Lead Teacher)

devacademy.co.nz

